Um...
（橋田 至(はしだいたる)）えっと… “実験結果”
"Experiment Result: Human is dead,
“ヒューマン イズ デッド
ミスマッチ”
mismatch."
Human is dead?
（岡部倫太郎(おかべりんたろう)）
“ヒューマン イズ デッド”？
（橋田）うん
Yeah.
Someone...
（岡部）人が…
...died?
死んだ？
（橋田）だと思う　多分…
I think so. Probably.
（岡部）その先は？
（橋田）ええと…
What does it say after that?
Let's see... The details are in Jellyman's report #143.
“詳細はゼリーマンズレポート
ナンバー14参照”
（岡部）
ゼリーマンズレポート？ 何だ？
Jellyman's Report?
What's that?
How should I know?
（橋田）
僕が分かるわけないっしょ
ただ こっちのサーバーに
妙なデータベースがあるから…
But there's a weird database on this server.
What's this?
（岡部）何だ これは？
Some kind of program code, I think.
（橋田）
多分 何かのプログラムのコード
（橋田）フフッ フフフフ…
（橋田）アハハ… 分かるかー！
（椎名(しいな)まゆり）あっ ダル君？
Daru?
I don't get it!
This doesn't make any sense!
こんなん絶対 分かんない！
死ね カスが！
Die! Damn it!
We should stop already.
もう やめたほうがいいよ
（橋田）ハア…
This is the first time I've had an "I was this close to getting it!" experience.
ここまでくれば楽勝と思ってた
時期が僕にもありました
Good job.
ご苦労だった　休んでいいぞ
Go ahead, and take a break.
You don't have to tell me. I'm done.
言われなくても もう無理…
（まゆり）
あっ ダル君 おでん缶あるよ
Daru, I've got canned fishcake stew.
（橋田）ありがと…
Thanks.
Program code...
（岡部）プログラムコード…
（阿万音鈴羽(あまねすずは)）ＩＢＮ5100は
The IBN 5100 was built before the widespread use of the BASIC language,
ベーシック言語が出来る以前に
作られたパソコンだから―
ＩＢＮ独自のプログラム言語も
読めるとか…
so it can read IBN's proprietary programming language or something...
I need the IBN 5100's abilities to stop their plans.
（ジョン･タイター）
“ＳＥＲＮ(セルン)の企(たくら)みを防ぐには”
“ＩＢＮ5100の機能が
必要なのです”
“あなたとは 一度ゆっくり
お話ししてみたい”
I'd like to talk to you in detail.
John Titor
This is my email address.
“私のメールアドレスです”
If you contact me, I'll answer.
“連絡いただければ
お返事します”
～
Enter Subject
There's something I want to ask you
To: John Titor
Subject: There's something I want to ask you
Interpreter
Rendezvous
There are a lot here.
（まゆり）ずいぶん多いね
Both Daru and I have been working all night and haven't been home.
（岡部）
俺もダルも ずっと徹夜続きで
家に戻っていないからな
And everything Daru wears, from his T-shirts to his underwear, is XXXL.
しかも ダルは
Ｔシャツからパンツまで―
ＸＸＸＬ(スリーエックスエル)だ
It's Feyris!
（まゆり）
ああっ フェリスちゃんが…
（鈴羽）岡部倫太郎！
Okabe Rintarou!
'Sup!
おっはー！
忠告しよう
I should warn you.
One, my name is Hououin Kyouma.
一つ 俺の名は鳳凰院凶真(ほうおういんきょうま)
一つ その挨拶は危険…
One, that greeting is dangero—
'Sup, Suzu!
（まゆり）おっはー 鈴(すず)さん
お前もか！
You too?
というか お前たち いつの間に？
Actually, when did you two meet?
We live in the same building.
（鈴羽）同じビルにいるからね
顔見知りにもなるよ
Naturally, we'd at least know each other's face.
Suzu gave me this Rai-Net card.
鈴さんには この
雷(らい)ネットカードをもらったのです
ゴールド！
It's gold!
（鈴羽）どこ行くの？
Where are you going?
To go do the laundry.
（まゆり）お洗濯だよ
Okarin and Daru have been up all night for days.
オカリンとダル君
徹夜続きだからね
（天王寺裕吾(てんのうじゆうご)）バイト！
（鈴羽）あっ
Part-timer!
（天王寺）
真面目にやらねえとクビにすっぞ！
If you don't do your job, I'll fire you.
（鈴羽）ヤバッ
Oh, no...
（天王寺）岡部も うちのバイトに
手をつけんじゃねえ！
You too, Okabe.
Keep your hands off my part-timer.
欲情しているのは―
Don't you think you're the one in love, Mr. Braun?
あなたのほうではないのか？
ミスターブラウン
Say that when Nae's around. I dare you.
（天王寺）てめえ
綯(なえ)がいる前で
そういうこと言ってみろ
マジで殺すからな
I'll seriously kill you.
Nae?
（岡部）綯？
ああ あの小動物か
The little squirrel?
Don't call my daughter a squirrel!
（天王寺）
人の娘を動物扱いすんじゃねえ！
How could I be in love with a little kid like her, anyway?
大体 俺が
そんなガキに欲情するか！
（鈴羽）むっ…
私はガキじゃない
一人前の戦士だよ！
I'm not a kid!
I'm an adult and a soldier!
はあ？
I like that look, part-time soldier.
（岡部）いい目だ バイト戦士
その目を忘れるな
Always remember that look.
そうすれば いつか
真の戦士へ クラスチェンジ…
If you do, someday, you'll be able to change classes to a true soldier—
いいから黙ってろ　お前が話すと…
You, shut up.
When you talk, it—
だから 私は もう戦士だってば！
I'm already a soldier!
（天王寺）
なんで うちの周りには―
Why do I get all the weirdos?
変なのばっかり
集まってくるんだろうな
ハア… じゃあね
Bye.
We, too...
俺たちも… ん？
That's a habit of Mayuri's.
（岡部）これは まゆりの癖だ
I've taken to calling it the "Stardust Handshake."
俺は勝手に―
スターダスト･シェイクハンドと
呼んでいる
（まゆり）
お星様に手が届かないかなあって…
I was wondering if I could reach the stars...
（岡部）星なんて見えないだろう
You can't even see the stars.
You know, even in daytime, the stars are still there.
（まゆり）あのねえ…
お昼でも
お星様は そこにあるんだよ
Those were powerful EM waves.
（牧瀬紅莉栖(まきせくりす)）
あれだけの電磁波よ
A cellular malfunction's a real possibility.
携帯電話が誤作動する可能性は
十分 考えられる
But I saw that banana.
でも バナナは確かに…
The Phone Microwave (name subject to change) is a time machine!
（岡部）
この「電話レンジ（仮）(かっこかり)」は
タイムマシンだ
The hell it is.
んなわけあるか！
ん…
ハア…
（まゆり）フェリスちゃーん
Feyris...
どうして
こんなんなっちゃったの？
Why'd this happen to you?
I'm closing the lid.
閉めるぞ
あ…
Daru is like the universe— constantly expanding.
（岡部）ダルは宇宙同様
日々 膨張を続けているからな
（岡部）おっ？
Shining Finger?
ああ シャイニング･フィンガーか
What's Titor doing?
タイターは何をしている？
メールをよこせと言っておいて…
He told me to message him.
Received Mail
Tell me how to reach the Super Haker!
“スーパーハカーさんの…”
Tell me how to...
しつこい！
Enough already!
（岡部）ん？
You have a new message
John Titor
Are you for real?
（岡部）ハア ハア…
（タイター）
“連絡ありがとうございます”
Thank you for the message.
Regarding the image you sent of that program,
“頂いたプログラムが表示された
画像ですが―”
it is indeed a proprietary programming language developed by IBN,
“確かに それはＩＢＮが独自に
開発したプログラム言語であり”
and decoding it will require an IBN 5100.
“解読するには
ＩＢＮ5100が必要なものです”
（岡部）ハア ハア… 聞け！
Listen to me!
これより未来ガジェット研究所は
緊急極秘作戦を発動させる！
The Future Gadget Lab will now initiate an emergency secret plan!
（橋田のいびき）
あ？
Okarin, what's wrong?
（まゆり）
オカリン 急に どうしたの？
Wake up, Daru!
（岡部）ダル 起きろ！
（橋田）うーん…
これから 世界を陰で操る
巨大な闇との戦いが始まるのだ！
We're about to engage in battle with
an immense organization that controls the world from the shadows!
（橋田）声デカいって もう…
It's SERN!
（岡部）ＳＥＲＮだ！
（橋田）ん…
やつらは
世界的な研究機関でありながら
They're a worldwide organization obsessed with dark science,
邪悪な研究に みいられて
巨大な陰謀を企てている！
and they're plotting a huge conspiracy!
The world only needs one mad scientist!
世界にマッドサイエンティストは
２人も要らん！
We must complete our quest before they do!
やつらに先んじられる前に
我らが出し抜いてやるのだ！
I don't understand what you're saying.
（まゆり）
何 言ってるか分かんないよ
First, we need an IBN 5100.
（岡部）とにかく
まずはＩＢＮ5100を手に入れ
Then, we'll decode SERN's mysterious program.
そしてＳＥＲＮの
謎のプログラムを解読する
出かける準備だ！
Get ready to leave!
でも まゆしぃは
今日はバイトなので…
But Mayushii has her part-time job today.
（いびき）
（岡部）結局 １人か…
So I get to do it alone...
（岡部）ん？
情報交換してみるのも手か…
Received Mail
Time:
Sender:The Lightning
Shiatsu-ist
Subject:Sorry if I'm bothering you.
Are you mad? Sorry if I'm bothering you. I
really need the IBN 5100 information, and
right now, you're the only one I can ask...
It might be worth exchanging information.
（紅莉栖）あっ
（岡部）ん？
Assistant?
助手か
Wait.
（岡部）待て
（紅莉栖）んあっ？
What?
何よ？
Come with me.
ちょっと来てもらおう
Hey! Wait!
な… ちょっと！
Geez, you destroyed the jacket's shoulder...
もう 肩んとこ
おかしくなっちゃったじゃない
Received Mail
Time:
Sender: The Lightning
Shiatsu-ist
Subject:
Let's both do
our best!
I don't have any real information.
How about you?
Moeka
“こっちの情報は ほぼなし”
"I don't have any real information."
役に立たんやつめ！
Useless!
Why are you glaring at me?
（紅莉栖）
なんで私がにらまれてるわけ？
気にするな　お前が原因ではない
Don't worry about it.
It's not your fault.
I'd rather you didn't blame me for your problems.
八つ当たりなら
やめてほしいんですけど
すねてるのか？
Are you sulking?
Mayuri was worried that you might've gotten upset.
まゆりも
へそを曲げたのではないかと―
心配していたぞ
You're too old to act like a little kid.
いい年をして
子どもじみたマネは よすのだな
あんたにだけは
言われたくない
You're the last person I want to hear that from.
Anyway, what did you want to talk to me about?
それより 話って何よ？
It's simple.
（岡部）簡単なことだ
Stop sulking, come back to the lab, and work, Christina.
いつまでもスネていないで
ラボに戻って働け クリスティーナ
（紅莉栖）せめて呼び名くらい
統一してほしいわけだが
I'd like you to at least stick to calling me one thing.
Listen to people when they're talking, "The Zombie."
（岡部）
人の話を聞け！ ザ･ゾンビ
Which of us isn't listening?
（紅莉栖）
聞いてないのは どっちだ！
ハア… どうして こんなのと
関わり持っちゃったんだろ
How'd I get involved with this guy?
I want to punch myself for giving in to my curiosity back then.
好奇心に負けた
あのときの自分を殴りたい
（岡部）なっ… またか！
Again?
そんなにイヤなメールなの？
Are those messages that annoying?
Yes, you wouldn't believe it...
（岡部）あまりにも常識外れな…
ハッ！ もしや
あの女も機関のエージェント…
Is she also an Organization agent?
（紅莉栖）機関？ 何それ
Organization? What's that?
（岡部）機関は機関だ
The Organization is the Organization!
世界を陰から操る
国家を超越した秘密組織であり…
It's an international secret organization, controlling the world from the shadows!
That's just a conspiracy theory, thank you very—
どう見ても陰謀論です
本当に ありが… あっ
どうした？
What's wrong?
なっ 何でもない
N-Nothing.
ん？
Really, it's nothing!
（紅莉栖）
ホント 何でもないから！
それ以上 追求したら殴るわよ！
Any more questions, and I'll hit you!
Blaming others for your problems?
（岡部）フン 八つ当たりか
ついてこい
洗濯物を回収後 任務を与える
Come with me.
After we recover the laundry, I'll give you your mission.
はあ？
のこのこ ついていくとでも…
You really think I'd follow you—
Laundry?
洗濯？
へえー こんな所にあったんだ
So there's a place like this, too.
There isn't one at the hotel?
（岡部）
ホテルには ついていないのか？
No, it's a pretty nice hotel....
（紅莉栖）結構 いいホテルだから
ついてないのよ
Still, it's not my style to send everything I wear to the cleaners.
かといって 着た物 全部
クリーニングに出すのも―
性に合わなくて
You found it, thanks to me.
（岡部）
俺のおかげで見つかったのだ
感謝して…
You should be gratef—
あれ？ 変化なしか
No change?
Of course not.
（紅莉栖）当たり前でしょ
回ってれば何かが起きるとか
思ってない？
You don't think something'll happen when it spins, do you?
The answer lies in the components we find most natural.
（岡部）
当たり前と思われるところにこそ
答えは隠されているものだ
そもそも―
Who would expect that hooking a cell phone to a microwave
電子レンジと電話をつなげた物で
タイムマシンが生まれ…
would make a time machine—
It's not a time machine!
（紅莉栖）タイムマシンじゃない！
（岡部）ああ？
あれは何かの間違いよ
That was some kind of mistake!
Time machines only exist in science fiction.
（紅莉栖）
タイムマシンなんて存在するのは
トンデモ科学の世界だけ
I'll have no part of it.
私は そんなものには くみしない
Why do you try so hard to deny what you saw?
（岡部）なぜ そこまで
自分の目で見たものを否定する？
（紅莉栖）別に…
I'm not...
ハッ！ もしや 過去のトラウマ？
Could it be some kind of past trauma?
Yes, it happened when she was five.
そう あれは５歳のころ―
Christina was struck by lightning on the grassy plains of Arkansas...
クリスティーナは
アーカンソーの草原で雷に…
（紅莉栖）打たれとらんわ
No, I wasn't.
Then why?
（岡部）なら なぜだ？
（紅莉栖）言ってるでしょ
I told you.
It's theoretically impossible.
理論上 ありえないからよ
Theories are nothing more than words.
（岡部）
理論など 単なる言葉遊びにすぎん
Accept what you've seen.
いいかげん
目の前で起きたことを認めるんだな
I refuse.
（紅莉栖）イヤよ
（岡部）フッ 何を いこじに…
Why are you being so stubb—
I said I refuse!
（紅莉栖）イヤだって言ってる！
私は…
I...
don't want to make the same mistake my father made!
父と同じ失敗は繰り返さない！
（岡部）ん？
ごめん… 感情的になった
I'm sorry.
I got emotional.
フッ…
（岡部）フーッハハハハ！
Don't worry.
気にすることはない
I deliberately provoked you to see what you'd do—
今は お前の資質を確かめるために
わざと怒らせたのだから…
Anyway, the Phone Microwave isn't a time machine.
（紅莉栖）とにかく 電話レンジは
タイムマシンなんかじゃない
I understand.
（岡部）分かった
I'm sorry I forced you to join the lab.
無理にラボメンに誘って悪かったな
もう来なくていい
You don't have to come anymore.
But I'll tell you this...
だが これだけは
伝えておく
No one else will ever have the title of Lab Member 004.
ラボメンナンバー００４は
永久欠番とする
この番号は
ずっとお前のものだ
That number will be yours forever.
What do you think you're doing?
（紅莉栖）
何 カッコつけてんのよ！
（岡部）うわっ がっ！
What are you doing?
何をする！
粋な別れの演出だったのに
That was a great parting speech!
And that's what bugs me.
（紅莉栖）それが頭に来るの！
You still have your laundry, right?
あんた 洗濯物 残ってるでしょ
私が出て行く　じゃあね
I'll leave.
Bye.
わっ！ 何よ？
What?
（岡部）お返しだ
己の軽率な行動を反省するのだな
I'm getting back at you.
You should reflect on your thoughtless actions.
（紅莉栖）んぐっ…
はいはい じゃあね
Right, right.
Bye.
Wait.
（岡部）待て
（紅莉栖）なっ…
Don't grab me there!
そこをつかむな！
Do you know anything about the IBN 5100?
（岡部）ＩＢＮ5100について
何か知っているか？
（紅莉栖）ＩＢＮ？
IBN?
（岡部）古いパソコンだ
It's an old PC.
（紅莉栖）何に使うの？
What are you going to use it for?
You want to know?
（岡部）気になるか？
You do.
気になるのだな
Geez...
あー もう！
Just a bit.
少しだけね
フッ
The IBN 5100 is connected to SERN's secrets.
ＩＢＮ5100は
ＳＥＲＮの秘密につながっている
はあ？
SERN is researching time travel,
（岡部）
ＳＥＲＮはタイムトラベルについて
研究しており
and to decode their secret program,
その秘密のプログラムを
解明するには―
we need the IBN 5100's special functionality.
ＩＢＮ5100の特別な機能が
必要なのだ
どうだ 驚いたか？
Well?
Surprised?
（紅莉栖）フン
（岡部）あ？
（紅莉栖）
バカみたい　聞いて損した
How stupid.
I'm sorry I listened.
（岡部）
なっ 鼻で… 鼻で笑った？
You... You snorted!
おのれ～ 必ず
その生意気な鼻を明かしてやる！
Why, you...
I'll show you!
So just you wait! Christina!
首を洗って待っているがいい
クリスティーナ！
There's no "-tina"...
だから ティーナじゃないっつうの
SERN is researching time travel.
（岡部）
ＳＥＲＮはタイムトラベルに…
ＩＢＮ5100の特別な機能が
必要なのだ
We need the IBN 5100's special functionality.
（岡部）
…ったく 気になるって言うから
教えてやったのに
Geez... I told her because she said she wanted to know.
（フェイリス）パソコン？
A PC?
Yeah. An old PC...
（まゆり）うん 古いパソコン
Like, it costs 5,100 yen or something?
たしか 5100円くらいするとか…
5,100?
（フェイリス）
5100？ もしかして…
Could it be...
（岡部）ん？
（まゆり）
トゥットゥルー オカリン？
Okarin!
Hey, hey! Mayushii heard something amazing.
あのねあのね まゆしぃは
すごいことを聞いちゃったのです
No Cell Phones
No cell phones.
Feyris said she's seen the PC you're looking for.
フェリスちゃんが見たことあるって
オカリンが探してるパソコン
No Cell Phones
No cell phones!
（店員）携帯禁止… うわっ
（岡部）プハーッ！
（店員）えっ？ あ…
ちょ… ちょっと！
H-Hey!
…ったく
Geez...
…って 足りないじゃない！
That's not enough!
Feyris Meow Meow! Feyris Meow Meow!
（男性客たち）
フェイリス ニャンニャン！
Feyris Meow Meow! Feyris Meow Meow!
フェイリス ニャンニャン…
Feyris Meow Meow!
何だ？ これは…
What's this?
Everyone!
（フェイリス）皆さーん
It's yours truly! Meow!
お待たせしたニャン！
まもなくフェイリス杯
昼の部を始めるニャ
We're starting the Feyris Cup daytime group!
All of you, do your best to beat Feyris
みんなが全力で
フェイリスに勝って―
and win a special Meow Meow Omelet Rice!
特製ニャンニャンオムライスを
ゲットするニャーよ！
（男性客たち）うおおーっ！
Feyris Meow Meow! Feyris Meow Meow!
フェイリス ニャンニャン！
Wha—
（岡部）な… 何だ？ この空間は
What's this?
Okarin!
（まゆり）あっ オカリン！
トゥットゥルー！
Mayuri...
まゆり…
な… 何が起きている？
時空間が ゆがんだか？
What's going on here?
Some kind of space-time distortion?
違うよ フェリス杯だよ
No, it's the Feyris Cup.
はあ？
Feyris is going to play Rai-Net Battler with everyone.
（まゆり）フェリスちゃんが
お客さん みんなと―
雷ネットバトルするんだよ
Kyouma!
（フェイリス）あっ 凶真！
Are you going to participate too?
凶真も参戦するニャ？
フェイリスは10人まで
一度に お相手できるニャ
Feyris can play up to ten at a time.
だから まだ…
So there's still...
I refuse!
（岡部）断る！
（フェイリス）ニャニャ？
それよりＩＢＮ5100だ
どこにある？
More importantly, the IBN 5100!
Where is it?
Well...
それは…
I'll tell you if you play.
参戦したら教えてあげるニャン
（岡部）
なっ… バカなことを言うな！
Don't be stupid!
The fate of the planet's power structure depends on this!
世界の構造が変わるかどうかの
瀬戸際なんだぞ
Some stupid game—
たかがゲームなど…
If you won't play, then I'm sorry, but you'll have to leave.
参戦しないなら―
ごめんニャさいだけど
お引き取り願うニャ
メイドの分際で
主人を帰らせる気か！
You're just a maid, and you're having your master leave?
ＩＢＮ…
The IBN 5100—
聞かないニャーン
I'm not listening!
くっ この…
（岡部）時間がない
There's no time.
I'm sorry, but I'll have to go all out.
申し訳ないが
手加減なしで いかせてもらう
You're really confident.
（フェイリス）ニャニャ？
すごい自信だニャ
Okarin, can you win?
（橋田）オカリン 勝てるん？
フェイリスたんは全国レベルだお
Feyris is one of the country's best players.
“勝てる”？
Can I win?
フッ それは
フェイリスにかけるべき言葉だな
You should be asking Feyris that.
I have a plan that's never failed.
俺には全戦必勝の作戦が
あるのだから
A plan?
（橋田）作戦？
（岡部）フフン
Plan Code:
作戦コード―
G-B-A-C-K.
Ｇ　Ｂ　Ａ　Ｃ　Ｋ！
名付けて…
I call it G-Back!
Ｇバック！
（会場のどよめき）
なんか すごそうだよ
That sounds pretty amazing!
This'll be fun.
面白そうニャ
You may say that now,
（岡部）
そんなこと言っていられるのも
今のうちだ
この作戦が さく裂したときは―
but when this plan explodes, you might not survive.
お前の命は ないのかもしれんの
だからな フフフ…
You're serious, aren't you, Kyouma?
本気だニャ 凶真
Let's make this clear:
先に言っておくぞ
If I participate, you'll tell me everything.
参戦した暁には―
知っている情報は
すべて吐いてもらう　いいな？
Understood?
（フェイリス）フン
猫耳に二言(にごん)はないニャ　勝負！
The cat ears never lie.
Let's begin!
教えてやろう
決して勝てない相手がいることを！
I'll teach you that you just can't beat some opponents!
I lost!
（岡部）参りました！
（橋田）早っ！
So fast!
Mayushii's disappointed.
（まゆり）
まゆしぃはガッカリなのです
What was your plan, actually?
（橋田）
いったい作戦て何だったん？
さあ… ただ 凶真は―
Who knows?
But he just kept charging me, like he was self-destructing.
自爆するみたいに
次々と突っ込んできただけだニャ
Self-destruct?
（まゆり）自爆…
（橋田）え？
Self-destruct... G-Back?
Note: Self-destruct - Jibaku
じー 爆…
（まゆり）Ｇバック？
（岡部）フフ…
That was a horrible joke, thank you very—
（橋田）どう見てもダジャレです
ホントにありがとうございました
However!
（岡部）しかーし！
（橋田）何ぞ？
What?
He recovers quickly.
Tell me what you know, Feyris.
情報は教えてもらうぞ フェイリス
負けたのに偉そうだニャ
You're arrogant for a loser.
（岡部）フフフ…
I said if I participated, you'd tell me what you know.
俺は“参戦した暁には
情報を吐いてもらう”と言ったのだ
つまり最初から勝ち負けなど
どうでもよかったのだよ
In other words, I never cared about winning.
そうなの？
Is that right?
I don't really remember...
よく覚えてないニャン
Remember it!
（岡部）いや覚えておけよ
頭脳的 我が戦略を！
It was my brilliant plan!
Brilliant or cheating, one of the two.
頭脳的っていうか汚(きたね)えっつうか…
Shut up!
黙れ！
Where's the IBN 5100?
ＩＢＮ5100は どこにある！
I don't know...
さあ…
You don't know?
知らないのか？
小さいころ パパが持ってたのは
確かニャんだけど…
I'm sure when I was little, Dad had one, but it's gone now.
今は もうないニャ
なっ！ 貴様…
Why, you...
Is that the secret move you mastered in Guiana Highlands, the Question-Dodge?
まさか それが ギアナ高地で
習得したという奥義―
肩すかし！
How'd you know?
なぜ分かったニャ？
Way to go, Kyouma.
さすが 凶真
You saw through my Cold Shoulder.
フェイリスのスルーショルダーを
見破るニャンて
Is that really it?
（岡部）本当に それだけか？
Yeah.
（フェイリス）そうニャ
I'm pretty sure the last time I saw it was at an Akihabara shrine.
最後に見たのは たしか
秋葉原(あきはばら)の神社だったニャー
Shrine?
神社？
"Kurisu,
（紅莉栖）“紅莉栖
遠く日本からメールありがとう”
thank you for messaging us all the way from Japan."
"I asked the professor about your question, and he said that,
“質問の件だけど―”
“教授に聞いたら
確かにＩＢＮ5100には―”
yes, the IBN 5100 can analyze certain special programming languages."
“特殊なプログラム言語を解析する
機能が ついていたってさ”
ホントだっていうの？
He was serious?
（漆原(うるしばら)るか）
えっ パソコンですか？
A PC?
I'll have to ask my father.
ちょっと
お父さんに聞いてみないと…
An IBN 5100.
（岡部）ＩＢＮ5100だ
If he doesn't know what that is, tell him it's an old computer.
分からなければ
古いパソコンと言えばいい
All right.
（るか）
分かりました 聞いてみます
I'll ask him.
I'm counting on you.
（岡部）頼む
End with the code words.
最後に合言葉を
E-El... Psy Congri...
（るか）
エ… エル･プサイ･コンガリィ？
コングルゥだ！
It's Congroo!
フウ…
（岡部）ん？
Hello?
もしもし
It's Makise.
（紅莉栖）牧瀬です
Makise?
マキセ？ 悪いが思い出せない
Sorry, I don't remember any Makise's.
Where'd we meet?
どこで会った？
パリか ロンドンか…
Paris? London?
（紅莉栖）秋葉原！
さっき会っただろうが
Akihabara.
I just saw you!
（岡部）なっ…
What? It's my assistant?
なんだ 助手ではないか
クリスティーナと言えば済むものを
Just say "Christina"!
There's no "-tina"!
（紅莉栖）ティーナじゃない！
You're as loud and bossy as ever.
（岡部）相変わらず
キャンキャンと うるさいな
Whose fault is that? Whose?
（紅莉栖）誰のせいだ 誰の！
What do you want?
（岡部）何の用だ？
（紅莉栖）ハア… 今 どこ？
Where are you now?
聞いてどうする？
Why do you care?
No reason.
（紅莉栖）別に
これから柳林(やなばやし)神社に
向かおうと思ってい…
I'm heading to Yanabayashi Shrine—
なっ…
What was that?
何だ？ 嫌がらせか？
嫌がらせなのか？
Harassment?
Was that harassment?
What was that call about?
（岡部）さっきの電話は何だ？
I just asked where you were.
（紅莉栖）
あんたの居場所を聞いただけ
No one called you.
（岡部）誰も呼んだ覚えはないが
No one called me.
誰も呼ばれた覚えはない
I'm back!
（るか）お待たせしました
Did you ask him?
（岡部）おお 聞いてくれたか？
Yes, he said that we have that PC here.
はい お父さんに聞いたら―
そのパソコンなら 確かに
うちの神社に奉納されてるって
Really?
（岡部）本当か！
PC?
パソコンって…
Do you mean an IBN 5100?
もしかしてＩＢＮ5100？
Yes.
はい
Um, who is this person?
あの… こちらの方は？
My assistant.
助手だ　それで ＩＢＮ…
Anyway, the IBN—
（紅莉栖）待てい！
Wait!
What kind of introduction was that?
何？ その適当な紹介のしかた
And I'm not your assistant!
つうか そもそも助手じゃないし！
I'm not here to introduce you.
（岡部）俺はお前を紹介するために
ここに来たのではない
（紅莉栖）
10秒もかからないでしょ？
It wouldn't even take ten seconds.
You're a pain, you know that?
（岡部）面倒くさいやつだな…
Makise Kurisu, my assistant.
牧瀬紅莉栖　助手だ
Right, right.
はいはい　いいですよ 助手で
Fine, I'm your assistant.
So who are you?
…で あなたは？
U-Urushibara Ruka.
う… 漆原るかです
How old are you?
（紅莉栖）おいくつなの？
Seventeen this year.
今年で17歳です
One year younger than me.
（紅莉栖）１個下か…
えっ？ そうなんですか？
Really?
You look like a grownup, Miss Makise.
牧瀬さん 大人っぽいですね
キレイだし
You're pretty.
そんな… あなたのほうこそ
No... Not nearly as pretty as you.
え？ あっ あの…
Um... I'll call my dad.
お父さん 呼んできます！
フン 知らぬが仏だな
Ignorance is bliss, huh?
What do you mean?
どういう意味？
I never thought it would happen.
（漆原栄輔(えいすけ)）いやあ しかし
まさか現実になるとは
Wh-What do you mean?
（岡部）ど… どういうことです？
Um, well, the person who donated this told us...
（漆原）
いえね 奉納されに来た方から
言われたんですよ
that someday, a young man who needed it would appear,
いつか このパソコンを必要とする
若者が現れるから―
so take good care of it.
大事に取っておくようにと
It was ten years ago, I think?
10年くらい前だったでしょうか
So that's it...
そんなことが…
It's fate.
まさに運命の符合
シュタインズ･ゲートの選択！
The choice of Steins Gate!
That again?
（紅莉栖）また それか
（紅莉栖）“ＩＢＮ5100
ポータブルコンピューター”
IBN 5100 Portable Computer.
This is it.
間違いない
Is that right?
（漆原）
それで よかったんですかね？
（岡部）
あの これをお借りできますか？
Um, could we borrow it?
いいですよ
Certainly.
（岡部）ああ… 感謝します！
Thank you.
We're carrying this back! Help me!
運ぶぞ　手伝え
But I refuse.
（紅莉栖）だが断る
You're my assistant, Christina!
（岡部）
助手だろう クリスティーナ！
I'm not your assistant, and there's no "-tina"!
（紅莉栖）助手でもないし
ティーナでもない！
I'll get a cart.
（漆原）
台車を持ってきましょう
We couldn't ask you for that, after you lent this to us.
貸してもらううえに
そんなことまで…
Hey, assistant!
おい助手！ 空気を読め！
Read the situation!
はあ？ 空気を読めって言った？
あんたが？
Read the situation?
You really just said that?
（漆原）
アハハ… 仲がよろしいですね
You guys are good friends, huh?
Be nice to Ruka too.
るかも仲良くさせてもらうんだぞ
Yes, please.
はい
Wait just a moment.
（漆原）
ちょっと待っててくださいね
いい お父さんね
You have a nice father.
え… そうですか？
You think so?
I don't want to make the same mistake my father made!
（紅莉栖）
父と同じ失敗は繰り返さない！
（岡部）ふむ…
（紅莉栖）何よ？
What?
Nothing.
（岡部）別に
I'm sorry!
（漆原）すみませーん
The cart's broken.
台車 壊れてしまっているようで…
（紅莉栖）ハア ハア…
Why do I have to do this with you?
なんで あんたと
こんなことに なっているのよ？
Shut up and carry it.
（岡部）
黙って運べ　まだ道のりは長いぞ
We've still got a long way to go.
（紅莉栖）う…
Hey...
（紅莉栖）あのさ…
（岡部）何だ？
What?
（紅莉栖）何でもない
（岡部）どおっとっとっ…
It's nothing!
What's with your provocations?
（岡部）貴様
なんだ その挑戦的な態度は！
（紅莉栖）うわあっ コラ 待ってよ
後ろ歩きになっちゃうでしょ！
Wait!
If you carry it like that, I'll have to walk backward!
Start walking, assistant!
（岡部）きびきび歩け 助手よ
（紅莉栖）ちょっ 無理！
後ろ歩きは さすがに無理！
I can't...
I can't walk backward!
You can do it, Assistant!
（岡部）助手なら できるはずだ
（紅莉栖）
期待してくれて どうも
でも無理！
Thanks for the words of support, but no!
I suggest we walk sideways!
横歩きへ変更求む　つうか しろ！
転んじゃうから！
Actually, we need to!
I'm going to trip!
～